Jerry Spicklemire

1402 Wolf Circle Indianapolis IN 46229 jspicklemire@gmail.com (317) 414-6931

Objective:

A Python Development position where experience in RDBMS and Linux cluster driven Object DB (REST / No-SQL) backed web applications, such as content management and work-flow, programming in Python, SQL, JavaScript, and shell, plus work with ETL, reporting, and web publishing in XHTML, CSS, and recent use of AWS, EC2 and RDS, will support new and ongoing software development.

Tech Skills:

Content: Web Publishing / Content Management, Zope*, GIS

Database: Oracle, Sybase ASE, MySQL, PostgreSQL, Couchbase ('NoSQL', json document DB) Development: LXC, Virtualbox, Vagrant, Eclipse, Aqua Data Studio, Info Modeler (Visio Modeler)

LAN / Com: TCP/IP, WiFi, HTTP, SSH, SSL, SMTP, FTP, SCP, POP

Languages: Python, JavaScript, SQL, PL/SQL, Transact SQL, PostScript, shell Network: copper (10baseT, etc.), fiber, switches, routers, firewalls (pf, firestarter)

OS: Linux (Ubuntu, Red Hat / Fedora / Centos, SuSE, Debian), UNIX (Solaris, HPUX,

BSD), MS Windows 3 - 7, OSX

Versioning: svn, git, cvs, hg, dpkg / apt

Web / Cloud: Amazon AWS, Apache, HTML, XML, XML-RPC, XHTML, CSS, JSON, JOuery,

Work History:

Xavient Information Systems, American Fork, UT Python Document DB analyst

Sep 2014 – present

Duties: Maintain and optimize JSON data file import / export process system, and formalize build and installation (DevOps) for web scale applications via AWS / EC2 with LXC, on Ubuntu server, using Python v.2.7, dpkg / apt for packaging, and Virtualbox / Vagrant for dev / test.

Judge Technical Staffing, Phildelpha, PA RDBMS Analysis, Python Data Exchange Development

Jan 2014 - May 2014

Duties: Analyze existing data within systems used by a recent acquisition, develop ETL process and mapping into present data schema of client systems. Add automated inbound / outbound file exchange with business partners, using Python v3.3, SFTP, FTP.

Python Web Application Development, Maintenance

Duties: Add new features, and improve existing functionality of a Web based workflow application hosted on Amazon AWS / EC2 (Ubuntu Linux), with AJAX, jQuery, and the tinyMCE embedded text editor, with a MySQL database storage.

ISIS, Vanderbilt University, Nashville, TN

Nov 2011 – Dec 2011

Python / Git / Object DB Developer

Duties: Enable secure web publishing of git software repositories and Object DB storage / retrieval. (Work History, continued)

Verio Inc., Boca Raton FL, an NTT Company Python / PEAK / SQL Developer

Aug 2006 – Oct 2011

Duties: Maintained corporate Service Request (ticketing) system, based on PEAK (Python Enterprise Application Kit), with OpenLDAP directory and Sybase ASE datastore. Added new features as requested by internal end users and business partners, accessing the system via web interfaces, and E-Mail.

Kobie Marketing, St. Petersburg, FL

Mar 2005 – Mar 2006

Web / XML, Zope / Plone, Python Developer

Duties: Web Services development for national and international marketing projects. Segment monolithic service offerings into service modules, with both web (HTTP/HTML) and XML-RPC interfaces available to clients and end users.

Work History (continued):

Escavel, Indianapolis IN Systems Consultant

Sep 2001 – Mar 2005

Duties: Develop web sites and web based, data driven applications, provide systems, internet, and security support. Collaborated on development of Expert System software for business development and marketing, based on cross-platform GUI system for MS Windows, MacIntosh, and Linux / UNIX. Merged existing questionnaire database with three other external systems into a single, consolidated system with user selectable questions. Updated reporting, testing and questionnaire database for user selectable details. Database programming and systems development. Provided desktop and LAN support, including systems specification, budgeting, acquisition, and deployment.

American Trans Air (ATA), Indianapolis, IN Systems Engineer

Jul 1997 – Sep 2001

Duties: Developed internal web applications for ATA intranet, providing web based user access to Oracle database, in-house desktop support "trouble ticket" system, and intranet usage statistics (logs). Developed data exchange process (ETL) for importing SABRE (flight schedule and booking) data into Oracle RDBMS, for revenue management system. Maintained and enhanced Revenue Management System, including "Y2K" transition from older "Clipper" (dBase class) to Oracle RDBMS.

Education

Bachelor of General Studies, IUPUI, 1997, minor in Geography (GIS)

*Special Interest: Co-author of "Zope: Web Application Development Content Management", New Riders, 2001, ISBN 0735711100